<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>braunmagrin's Blog</title><link href="http://braunmagrin.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://braunmagrin.com/feeds/education.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://braunmagrin.com/</id><updated>2016-07-11T00:00:00-03:00</updated><entry><title>Paulo Freire, responsibility and data science</title><link href="http://braunmagrin.com/paulo-freire-responsibility-and-data-science.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-07-11T00:00:00-03:00</published><author><name>Matheus Braun Magrin</name></author><id>tag:braunmagrin.com,2016-07-11:paulo-freire-responsibility-and-data-science.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'd like to start this post (and this blog) with a quote:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"(...) The more I train myself as a professional, the more I systematize my
experiences, the more I make use of the cultural heritage, which is everyone's
heritage and to which everyone must serve, the more my responsibility with the
men increases."&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:1" rel="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a free translation of a Paulo Freire's&lt;sup id="fnref:2"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:2" rel="footnote"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; quote from "Education and change".
This expresses how I've been feeling about all the cool things I've learned so
far. In fact, I did almost all of my education for free. I've studied in public
schools and in a public university, which were paid by everyone. And nowadays I've
been using a lot of freely available online resources. It's about time to start sharing
and hopefully help other people to learn as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why I've choosen a blog?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've chosen to do so in a blog because it's an flexible medium. It allows for several
types of content. The blog format also suits my other objectives, which are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to keep a lerning log, so that I can revisit stuff that I've learned; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improve my writing skills, both in Portuguese, my mother tongue, and in English.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Who am I?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm a Brazilian. I currently work as a Data Scientist at &lt;a href="http://www.bravi.com.br"&gt;Bravi&lt;/a&gt;,
where we build a Learning Analytics platform. I've studied Computer Science in college.
Today the tools I use and like the most are Python, the SciPy stack and Jupyter Notebooks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I aspire to be an educator. Unfortunately, the specific subject is yet to be decided.
I keep changing my mind from technology and data science related areas to something related
to Permaculture and sustainable living.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really like the whole &lt;a href="https://www.gnu.org/philosophy/floss-and-foss.en.html"&gt;FLOSS&lt;/a&gt;
idea. Actually, I also like other "Open" things, like Open Science, Open Access, Open
Data, Open Education and so on. I really think that the knowledge and technologies
should benefit everyone and one great way of doing so is to the make them publicly
available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is this blog about?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here you can expect to see posts about a lot of topics, but the ideia is to keep the main
focus on Data Science. When I was still thinking if I would create this blog I listed the
topics I like, and therefore, that I would like to study and share with you. I've created
a mind map&lt;sup id="fnref:3"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:3" rel="footnote"&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; that you can see below. I guess it'll take a while, but someday I'll talk about them all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Subjects mind map" src="http://braunmagrin.com/images/mindmap_transparent.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Free translation of "(...) Quanto mais me capacito como profissional, quanto
mais sistematizo minhas experiências, quanto mais me utilizo do patrimônio cultural,
que é patrimônio de todos e ao qual todos devem servir, mais aumenta minha
responsabilidade com os homens." Paulo Freire in Educação e Mudança, p.20&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:2"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paulo Freire is a Brazilian educator. Arguably one of the most influential,
at least one of the most cited ones according to &lt;a href="http://blogs.lse.ac.uk/impactofsocialsciences/2016/05/12/what-are-the-most-cited-publications-in-the-social-sciences-according-to-google-scholar/"&gt;this study&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:2" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 2 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:3"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This mind map was created using &lt;a href="https://www.mindmup.com/"&gt;MindMup&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:3" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 3 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="education"></category><category term="knowledge"></category><category term="learning"></category><category term="sharing"></category><category term="free/libre and open"></category></entry></feed>